TO: THE MANAGER,

SUB: APPLICATION FOR SALES MANAGER

Dear Sir,

I have been working in DUBAI, UAE /QATAR / OMAN for the past 30 YEARS in the field of SECURITY SYSTEMS at various levels, the last being Sales Manager of a very prestigious company in Oman. I have extensive professional experience in all aspects of various Security Systems including Installation, Sales & Marketing and Sourcing Products from all over the world as well as successfully handling multinational clientele & executing projects to profitable completion.

Attached pl. find my detailed Resume for your kind perusal. Should you find it interesting in anyways or should you find me a right candidate for your esteemed organization for a suitable post, I will be glad to visit you for further discussion.

Hoping for your kind assistance & awaiting your valuable reply.

Thanking you,

Yours sincerely,

Suren Desai.

GSM - +974 7004 0621

E-mail – scorpiosuren@hotmail.com

WhatsApp: +974 7004 0621

Suren Desai

E-mail: scorpiosuren@hotmail.com

GSM: +974 7004 0621

EXPERIENCE

28 Years of Comprehensive Experience in Installations,
Commissioning, Sales and Marketing, Tendering, Man Management and Project Managements of various systems, i.e.
Intruder Alarm Systems, Integrated Access Control, CCTV &
CCTV Network, Perimeter Security, Biometric Access, Anti-Shop
Lifting Systems, Intercom & Video Phones, Automatic Barriers
& Car Park Management Systems, Vehicle Tracking & GPS
System, P.A. & Music Systems and various other systems.

I started my career with Larsen and Toubro in Mumbai in 1973 and my last few postings have been with –

UNIVERSAL SECURITY SYSTEM - DOHA QATAR (SINCE DEC 2016 TILL DATE) BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

Various Commercial & Ministerial ELV Projects such as: Ministry of Interior (MOI), Amiri Guard (Govt of Qatar), Al Ruwais Port, Doha Festival City, Aster Hospital, Nakhilat Office Tower, Extreme Entertainment Centre-Mall of Qatar, Total Fresh Hypermarket

BIOENABLE TECHNOLOGIES PVT LTD - INDIA (SINCE APRIL 2015 TO JAN 2016) Sr. BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANEGER FOR MIDDLE EAST

Promoting Company Products & Developing Business leads & contacts in Middle East markets for Software Development & Customization, HRMS Software, Biometric Access & Time Attendance, Biometric Iris Recognition Solution, Long Range RFID Solutions, Vehicle Tracking System & Platform, Energy Management Solution, Canteen Management Solution, Visitor Management System etc.

MAJEES TECHNICAL SERVICES L.L.C. - OMAN (MARCH 2011 TO SEPT 2013)

ASST. MANAGER - SALES

Various security projects for Residential, Commercial & Industrial complexes such as: OMANTEL Frame Contract for 3 years, OMAN OIL MARKETING COMPANY 55 Petrol Stations, Salman Corporation Pizza Inn & Photo Magic Outlets, Carillion Alawi, German Embassy, Oman Gas Company, Burger King,

MEDC, Daleel Corporation, Mouawad Jeweler, Daawat Restaurant, RGO Technical College, Shaksy Engineering, Bark Telecom, ISKAN Contracting, Oman Air Offices, OLNG Villa, etc.

QATAR SECURITY SERVICES - QATAR

(JUN 2010 TO NOVEMBER 2010)

36 Villa CCTV Project.

BAABOOD L.L.C. Oman. (SINCE MARCH 2008 TO MAY 2010)

Manager - Security Solutions

Various security projects for Residential, Commercial & Industrial complexes such as: Bank Muscat [30 Branches+30 ATMs],
Omantel, Enhance / Oman oil [20 Outlets], Safeer Plaza Hotel, Safeer International Hotel, Safeer Continental Hotel, Crown Plaza Salalah, Financial Services L.L.C., Carillion Alawi, Technoplast Industries, Oman Cables, Manam Hotel, Desert Chrome Metal Industries, Intercontinental Muscat Hotel, Al Ansari Trading, Salman Stores, Nestle Oman, IT Authority – Security, etc.

MAJAN SECURITY SYSTEMS L.L.C. - Oman. (DEC. 2002

to SEPT. 2007)

Divisional Manager

Various security projects for Residential, Commercial & Industrial complexes such as: Bank Muscat, Intercontinental Hotel, Crown Plaza Hotel, Hilton Salalah Hotel, Muscat Duty Free, Travelex, Embassy of Kuwait, Embassy of the Republic of Turkey, American British Academy, Shell, Unicef, Air India, Novotel Hotels, Sahara Hotel Apartments, Ministry Of Economy etc.

CITYTEC LLC. Dubai - U.A.E. (1999 to 2001)

Divisional Manager

Various security projects for Residential, Commercial & Industrial complexes such as: Damas Jewelers, Kanoo Group, Dubai Municipality, Dubai Immigration, Abu Dhabi Commercial Bank, Majid Al Futtaim, Etisalat, Dubai World Trade Centre, British Embassy, Intercontinental Hotel, etc

HITECH SECURITY SYSTEMS. Dubai – U.A.E. (1992 to 1999) **Sales and Operations Manager**

Various security projects for Residential, Commercial & Industrial complexes such as: Damas, Fitra International, ARY Jewelers, Ritz Carlton Hotel, Al Hseena Jewelers, Dubai Crown Plaza Hotel,

Central Bank Of Dubai, Central Bank OF Ras-Al-Khaimah, The Ruler's Court-Diwan, etc

HPS SECURITY SERVICES. Dubai – U.A.E. (1981 to 1991)

Sales & installation engineer

Various security projects for Residential, Commercial & Industrial complexes such as Port Authority of Jebel Ali, Central Bank of Abu Dhabi, Khalil Al Sayegh Jewellery Group, Zabeel Palace, Stradivarius group, Dubai Police Collage, Majestic – Cartier Showroom, GBM GROUP, ABN AMRO Bank, Sheraton hotel, World Trade Centre etc.

PRODUCTS HANDLED

INTRUDER ALARM G.E. Interlogix/C&K/Menvier/Scantronics/Texecom/Ademco/DSC

FIRE ALARM Secutron/Simplex

CCTV Kalatel/Deltavision/Pelco/Videotronics/Samsung/Axis/American

Dynamics/Mobotics/IRLab/Cop-Security/Flur(Thermal & Radar CCTV)/Aventura/Surveon/Arecon/Verint/VideoIQ/Vivotek

Access & TA HID/Fingertech/GE/Kantech/Position Technology/CEM Systems/

Nitgen/ZX Systems/L-1 Identity/Spica Int./Suprema/Actatek

SYSTEM

INTEGRATION Software House/CEM System/Lenel/Gallagher/Sightlogics/Synetics/

Milestone

PIDS Southwest Microwave/Gallagher/Sentrax

Intercom & Video Samsung/Fermax

Phone

Barrier & Gate

Automation

Nice/Broughton/RIB/Came

EAS System Unisen / Sensormatic

Queue System Q-tech

Home Automation Smart home / Smarti

PAVA Merlaud Systems

SMATV Televes

EDUCATION

Passed Secondary School Certificate Exam. In October, 1972 with First Class.

Passed NCTVT Mechanical Diploma Certificate Exam. In October, 1977 With First Class.

Passed Computer Programming in Basic Diploma in December 1987 with Second Class.

Attended 'Group 4 - Securitas, UK' Course in Security for practical and Design Standard in July, 1986.

SKILL SETS

Computer

Excellent familiarity with Microsoft Office suite, Word and Excel.

Languages

English and Hindi. Excellent command over the English language enabling, independent correspondence and liaison with International suppliers.

Workshops

Completed 'ISO 9001-2000 Awareness Seminar Training' conducted By 'Texas Management Consultants - USA' in January, 2001.

Special Interests & Hobbies

Enjoy Music, Painting, Traveling and Reading

Holding Valid Driving Licenses for U.A.E., OMAN & QATAR

PERSONAL	Passport #	L
----------	------------	---

8876919 Valid for UAE, Qatar and Sultanate of **Driving License**

Nationality Indian Civil Status Married

Permanent Address C/O Mr. B. G. Thakur, A-604 Mantri

> Elegance, Banarghatta Road, N.S.Palya Bangalore-560076,

Karnataka, India